Hyunji Amy Lee

hyunji.amy.lee@kaist.ac.kr | https://amy-hyunji.github.io/

RESEARCH INTEREST

Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning: information retrieval, knowledge representation, knowledge-augmented LMs, and reasonings.

My research goal is to build a robust semi-parametric model that aligns with external knowledge modules thereby capitalizing on the strengths of both the model's parametric knowledge space and external nonparametric knowledge space, aiming to achieve the optimal performance. I've focused on superposing parametric and nonparametric knowledge spaces [C4][C8], exploring retrieval models to find relevant external knowledge [C2][P2][C9][W1], and developing language models that ground well to external knowledge [C4][C7]. Additionally, I aim to extend these solutions to multi-modal challenges by merging representation spaces from various modalities [P1][C1][C3].

EDUCATION

KAIST AI

Ph.D. Candidate in AI Grad School. Advisor: Minjoon Seo Mar. 2023 – present

KAIST AI

M.S. in AI Grad School. Advisor: Minjoon Seo Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2023

KAIST

B.S. in Electrical Engineering & Computer Science (Double Major) Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Tencent AI Lab Seattle, US

Research Intern. Tencent AI Lab Sep 2024 ~ Present

Mentor: Wenhao Yu

Adobe Research San Jose, US

Research Intern, Vision Language Lab (Mentor: David Seunghyun Yoon, Trung Bui, Franck Dernoncourt) May 2024 ~ Aug 2024

Improving Question Answering over Real-World Corpus

Seattle, US Allen Institute for AI (AI2)

Research Intern, Semantic Scholar Team (Mentor: Kyle Lo, Luca Soldani, Arman Cohan) May.2023 - Dec. 2023 [P2]

Improving Out-of-Domain Dense Retriever

Developing Virtual Try-On Model (page)

MindLogic Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern (Mentor: YongWoo Kim) Dec. 2020- Feb. 2020

Developing a real-time korean QA Chatbot model

Naver Seongnam, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern (Mentor: Sohee Yang, Wonseok Hwang, Minjoon Seo) Mar. 2020 – Dec. 2020 [C1]

Developing a cost-effective parser model for semi-structured document images

SKT AI Seoul, Republic of Korea

AI Fellowship (Mentor: Eric Davis, Jaehoon Kim) June. 2019 - June. 2020

Building Efficient Koran Multi Sentiment Analysis Model (page)

MindLogic Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern (Mentor: YongWoo Kim) Dec. 2019 – Feb. 2019

Last Updated: Oct. 4, 2024

Naver

Research Scientist Intern, Developing Auto Colorization Model for Webtoon Mentor: Gayoung Lee

PUBLICATIONS

Conference and Journal Papers

[C9] Continually Updating Generative Retrieval on Dynamic Corpora

Soyoung Yoon, Chaeeun Kim, *Hyunji Lee*, Joel Jang, Minjoon Seo *EMNLP 2024*

[C8] SemiParametric Token-Sequence Co-Supervision

<u>Hyunji Lee*</u>, Doyoung Kim*, Jihoon Jun, Sejune Joo, Joel Jang, Kyung-Woon On, Minjoon Seo *Accepted in ACL 2024 (Long)*

[C7] How Well Do Large Language Models Truly Ground?

<u>Hyunji Lee*</u>, Sejune Lee*, Chaeeun Kim, Joel Jang, Kyung-Woon On, Minjoon Seo *Accepted to NACCL 2024 (Long)*ACL KnowledgeNLP Workshop 2024 Oral (Best Student Paper)

[C6] KTRL+F: Knowledge-Augmented In-Document Search

Hanseok Oh*, Haebin Shin*, Miyoung Ko, <u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Minjoon Seo Accepted to NACCL 2024 (Long)

ACL KnowledgeNLP Workshop 2024, ACL KnowledgeLM Workshop 2024

[C5] Improving Probability-based Prompt Selection Through Unified Evaluation and Analysis

Sohee Yang, Jonghyeon Kim, Joel Jang, Seonghyeon Ye, <u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Minjoon Seo Accepted to TACL 2024

[C4] Nonparametric Decoding for Generative Retrieval

<u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Jaeyoung Kim, Hoyeon Chang, Hanseok Oh, Sohee Yang, Vlad Karpukhin, Yi Lu, Minjoon Seo *Accepted to Findings of ACL 2023 (Long)*

[C3] Local 3D Editing via 3D Distillation of CLIP Knowledge

Junha Hyung, Sungwon Hwang, Daejin Kim, **Hyunji Lee**, Jaegul Choo Accepted to CVPR 2023

[C2] Generative Multi-hop Retrieval

Hyunji Lee, Sohee Yang, Hanseok Oh, Minjoon Seo Accepted to EMNLP 2022 (Long), AKBC 2022 Finalist Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship 2023

[C1] Cost-Effective End-to-End Information Extraction for Semi-Structured Document Images

Wonseok Hwang, <u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Jinyeong Yim, Geewook Kim, Minjoon seo Accepted to EMNLP 2021 (Short)

Posters and Workshop Papers

[W1] InstructIR: A Benchmark for Instruction Following of Information Retrieval Models

Hanseok Oh, <u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Seonghyeon Ye, Haebin Shin, Hansol Jang, Changwook Jun, Minjoon Seo *ACL KnowledgeNLP Workshop 2024 Oral*

Last Updated: Oct. 4, 2024

Preprints / Under Review

[P2] Knowledge Entropy Decay during Language Model Pretraining Hinders New Knowledge Acquisition

Jiyeon Kim*, **Hyunji Lee***, Hyowon Cho, Joel Jang, Hyeonbin Hwang, Seungpil Won, Youbin Ahn, Dohaeng Lee, Minjoon Seo

Preprint arxiv

[P2] RouterRetriever: Exploring the Benefits of Routing over Multiple Expert Embedding Models

Hyunji Lee, Luca Soldani, Arman Cohan, Minjoon Seo, Kyle Lo *Preprint arxiv*

[P2] Back to Basics: A Simple Recipe for Improving Out-of-Domain Retrieval in Dense Encoders

<u>Hyunji Lee</u>, Luca Soldani, Arman Cohan, Minjoon Seo, Kyle Lo

Preprint arxiv

[P1] Zero-Shot Dense Video Captioning by Jointly Optimizing Text and Moment

Yongrae Jo, Seongyun Lee, Aiden SJ Lee, *Hyunji Lee*, Hanseok Oh, Minjoon Seo *Preprint arxiv*

HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Best Student Paper	2024
ACL KnowledgeNLP Workshop 2024	
Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship	2023
Qualcomm, Finalist	
KAIST Graduation Leadership Awards KAIST	2021
Qualcomm-KAIST Multimodal Emotion Recognition Kaggle Qualcomm, 5th Prize	2020
SKT AI Fellowship SKT AI	2019
DKU (Duke & Duke-Kunshan Univ.) program as KAIST representative Duke & Duke-Kunshan Univ.	2018
KAIST Global Leadership Awards KAIST	2018
KAIST Leadership & Volunteering Awards KAIST	2017

Last Updated: Oct. 4, 2024